nationaleatingdisorders.org 2019-07-08

# NEDA Privacy Policy | National Eating Disorders Association

Last updated:  May 1, 2018

The National Eating Disorders Association (referred to herein as "NEDA", "we", "us", and "our"), a 501(c)3 non-profit organization, respects the privacy of individuals ("you", "your", and "users") who use our websites and services, and is committed to protecting it through adherence to this privacy statement.  The Policy applies to NationalEatingDisorders.org and NEDA-operated microsites (collectively the “Websites”), and describes the personal information that NEDA collects from the Websites and the ways in which NEDA uses the information.  It also informs you about our practices with respect to information that might be collected through NEDA's service partners and other online/offline channels.

By using the Websites or communicating with NEDA through online/offline channels, you are deemed to have assented and agreed to the Policy as in effect at the time of your use.

**Information Collected**

You can browse the content on the Websites without revealing any personal information.

From time to time, NEDA may provide the opportunity to participate in a survey on the Websites, requesting or allowing you to submit content that may be uploaded to the Websites.  In conducting a survey, we may ask you for certain information such as your age, gender, race, ethnicity, and your opinion about our services.  Participation will be voluntary and, if indicated as anonymous, it will not be linked to any personal information.

For certain online transactions with NEDA including making donations to, purchasing items or service from, or participating in auctions or events sponsored by or for the benefit of NEDA, you will be provided with a link to an SSL-secured website, which may be a third party’s website, to process your requests.  The types of personal information that would be collected are disclosed prior to or at the time of transaction.  Please read privacy policies and data collection practices of any third-party site that processes online transactions on behalf of NEDA.  We take no responsibility for the security and/or data collection practices of third parties.

To enhance your experience with the Websites, non-personal information may be collected through the use of "cookies."  These cookies are files commonly placed in your computer's web browser to store your preferences while using the Websites.  If you don’t want information collected through the use of cookies, you may delete, disable, turn off, or reject the cookies by changing your web browser settings.  However, disabling cookies might also disable some features of the Websites in which content can function only in conjunction with the cookies.

Some anonymous statistical data on the Websites such as usage patterns, visitor interests, technology used, demographics, and geographic information may be logged by third-party tools for the purpose of improving NEDA's services, monitoring the health of our Websites, and enhancing site usability.  To learn more about the collected data and how to opt-out, please visit Google's guide to [data privacy & security](https://support.google.com/analytics/topic/2919631?hl=en&ref_topic=1008008).

**Information Use**

NEDA does not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to other organizations or individuals in ways different from what is disclosed in the Policy.  NEDA is the sole owner of the information collected through its services and the Websites, and may use the information to assess NEDA's programs and for development efforts.  On occasion, we may share the information with third-party companies for the sole purpose of assisting NEDA in fulfilling such assessments and development efforts.

To respond to your requests and for updates about new content on the Websites and special events organized by NEDA, your email address in NEDA's database will be used to communicate.  NEDA may also directly communicate with you via phone and/or direct mail concerning non-anonymous surveys, submission of content, or services we provide.  Information collected from the communication will be stored as long as NEDA deems reasonably necessary and practicable for the purpose of enhancing our services, or to otherwise meet legal requirements.

Your personal information will only be accessible to authorized NEDA staff, consultants, agents, subcontractors and professional advisors, all of whom are contractually bound to honor the terms of this Privacy Policy.   **You acknowledge, consent, and agree that to the extent legally permissible in each applicable jurisdiction, NEDA may access, preserve, and/or disclose the information collected (including personal information) to a law enforcement agency or another third party if required to do so by law or if NEDA determines that access, preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (a) comply with legal process; (b) respond to claims that any content that you submit violates the rights of third parties; or (c) protect the safety, rights, or property of NEDA's visitors (including you) or others.**

**Accessing & Correcting Information**

You have the right to access, update, request removal of, and correct factual inaccuracies in personally identifiable information that is collected through the Websites, subject to the provisions in the preceding section.  To do so, you may email us at [info@nationaleatingdisorders.org](mailto:info@nationaleatingdisorders.org).  To protect your privacy and the security of your personally identifiable information, NEDA will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before updating, correcting, or removing your personally identifiable information.

**Security**

NEDA takes security seriously and will take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse, or alteration of your personal information.  NEDA will store all the personal information you provide on its secure servers.  Information relating to online transactions entered via the Websites will be protected by encryption technology.  However, there is no such thing as a 100% secure website.  The National Eating Disorders Association cannot, and does not guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking, data loss, disclosure, misuse, modification, or any other breaches will not occur.

**Links to External Sites**

The content on our Websites may include links to external websites that are not directly operated and maintained by NEDA.  These external sites have their own privacy policies and/or data collection practices, which may be substantially different from NEDA's, concerning personal information.  NEDA encourages you to review and learn about the privacy policies and practices of all external websites and services.  We take no responsibility for linked external sites.

**Images**

All images used on the Websites are for illustrative purposes only.  Any person depicted in the content/Websites is a model.  The depiction does not suggest that the model's endorsement of any business, product, service, cause, association, or endeavor of NEDA is expressed or implied, and that such person has or had eating disorders or any association with eating disorders.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

From time to time, NEDA may decide, or be required by law to make changes to this Privacy Policy.  If NEDA makes any material changes to the Policy that may impact how we use personal information, we will post the revised version to this webpage and notify you via regular communication channels.  You are encouraged to read NEDA's e-newsletters or to return to this page periodically for any update.

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about the Websites or the Privacy Policy, please email  **[info@nationaleatingdisorders.org](mailto:info@nationaleatingdisorders.org) **or contact us at:

National Eating Disorders Association  
1500 Broadway, Ste 1101  
New York, NY 10036

(212) 575-6200

**U.S. Governing Law**

The Websites are designed and targeted to users who reside in the United States and is governed by and operated in accordance with the laws of the United States.  We make no representation that the Websites are operated in accordance with the laws or regulations of, or governed by other nations.  By accessing and/or providing personal information through the Websites, you certify that you meet the legal requirements for disclosure of personal information in your jurisdiction.  If you do not meet the legal requirements, please contact us and request that we delete your personal information, and discontinue disclosing personal information through the Websites.  Continued use of the Websites and/or disclosure of personally identifiable information indicates that you are agreeing to the collection, use, disclosure, management, and storage of your personal and non-personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**For a resident of European Economic Area (EEA)**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from EEA residents, but if you are a resident of EEA and have provided any personal information to us, you have the following rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR):

\- If you wish to access, correct, update, or request deletion of your personal information, you can do so by emailing us at any time.  
\- You can object to processing, or ask us to restrict our processing personal information provided by you.  
\- You have the right to opt-out of email communications by clicking on the 'unsubscribe' link in the email footer.  
\- If you have previously consented to our data collection practice, you can withdraw your consent at any time.  
\- You have the right to complain about our use of your personal information to your local authority.

If you wish to exercise your rights under GDPR, please email us at any time.
